<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on Snowyurik&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://snowyurik.vihv.org/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on Snowyurik&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 22:19:56 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://snowyurik.vihv.org/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IT Management Paradox</title>
      <link>https://snowyurik.vihv.org/post/it-management-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 22:19:56 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snowyurik.vihv.org/post/it-management-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective management practices lead to small teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ineffective management practices lead to huge teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most people are involved in ineffective practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demand for ineffective management practices is higher, than denamd for effective practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education system follow the demand of the majority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education system teach ineffective management practices, because the demand is higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective management practices extinct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This explains all that billionairs with unfinished education: it&amp;rsquo;s better to know nothing, then to know wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tick-the-code&amp;rdquo; and similar practices are widely replaced by &amp;ldquo;intuition-based-review-of-single-commit&amp;rdquo; practices. Intuition based review is perfectly useless. Whatever you call it &amp;ldquo;expert review&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;experience based review&amp;rdquo; or whatever. Single commit review is also perfectly useless. All commits can be ideal, but together they can, and will, create nonsence. Bare minimum for review is 1 class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;old-school-agile-rule-of-thumb&#34;&gt;Old-school Agile rule of thumb&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it needs special tools - it&amp;rsquo;s bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IMHO, if the tool is just a replacement for pen and paper, but you still can do it with pen and peper - it&amp;rsquo;s ok. It&amp;rsquo;s not handy to use pen and paper in the age of remote work.
But anything more complex will only make things worse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
